tdstelecom.com 2011-11-05

# TDS Privacy Policy - TDS Telecom

Effective Date: August 24, 2009

### Commitment to Protecting Customer Privacy

TDS Telecommunications Corporation ("TDS") is dedicated to providing superior customer satisfaction and is committed to protecting customer privacy. We take this responsibility seriously as a key component to earning and maintaining our customers' trust.

### Scope

This Privacy Statement applies to TDS and any Third Party with whom we share or collect Confidential Personal Information. Third Party refers to agents, vendors, suppliers, subcontractors, and independent contractors. By subscribing to our services or accessing our Web sites, you agree to our collection and use of your information as described in this Privacy Statement as may be amended from time to time. It does not apply to services, products, or Web sites that do not display or link to this Privacy Statement or that have their own privacy statements. 

### Collection of your Confidential Personal Information

Confidential Personal Information is information that relates to you and identifies or can be used to identify you. This information includes your name, billing address, social security number, driver's license number, credit card number, bank account number, email address, and credit information. TDS may collect Confidential Personal Information for those purposes specified in this Privacy Statement, and as otherwise permitted by law.

We may collect Confidential Personal Information through a business office, over the phone, or online. You may choose to provide this information to us through a number of interactions such as by: 

  * Ordering a product or service from us
  * Sending us an email
  * Registering to receive information about our products or services
  * Applying for a job or a grant; or
  * Entering a contest.

We may also collect this information about you from trusted agents who are authorized to sell our products and services, or from employees of our Affiliates. Affiliates refers to any of the Telephone and Data Systems, Inc. owned companies.

We may ask you questions to better serve your special needs and interests. For example, we may ask whether you work at home, whether any members of your household have special needs or whether teenagers reside in your household in order to determine whether you may be interested in certain services. For training or quality assurance, we may also monitor or record our calls with you. 

As part of network operations and when you visit a TDS Web site, we automatically collect certain information such as your domain type, your IP address, and click stream information to gauge the effectiveness of our Web sites, improve our online operations, enhance your online experience with customized content, and focus our marketing efforts to better meet the needs of our customers. We also may collect Confidential Personal Information if you order a product or service through one of our Web sites the same as we would if you called us on the phone to place an order. 

We may store small data files known as cookies, or other similar technologies, on your computer or mobile browser when you visit one of our Web sites. Cookies allow TDS to personalize your service by collecting and storing information that will identify you when you visit a Web site. Cookies also allow us to collect ‘Web site usage' information when you visit our Web sites, including IP address, Web browser and operating system types, Web pages visited on our Web sites, time spent on our Web pages, and return visits to our Web sites. We may combine the Web site usage information with your Confidential Personal Information in order to provide a more customized online experience to you and to provide advertising about goods and services that may be of particular interest to you. These same cookies may also be used by our advertising partners on TDS and other Web sites to display advertisements based on the preferences you demonstrate through your online activities. We do not track user click stream or other information resulting from activity on sites that are not operated by TDS.

You may be able to disable cookies on your computer; however if you do so, you may limit your experience on that Web site, including finding pricing and availability of products and services in your area from our Web site. You can set your browser to delete cookies or to tell you before you accept one. Look in your browser's Options or Preferences menu. 

TDS is not responsible for the practices, including the use of cookies, employed by Web sites linked to or from our Web site or for the content contained therein. The Web sites and services you are able to access on the Internet are outside the control and limits of this privacy policy.

### Use of your Confidential Personal Information

We may use your Confidential Personal Information to provide you with and manage the services you request, communicate with you to maintain good customer relations or to suggest new products and services that may be of interest to you, personalize the content we deliver, conduct industry or consumer surveys, manage, improve and troubleshoot our network and services, enforce our Terms of Service, or for any purpose otherwise permitted or required by law.

When you want to set up an account with TDS, in order to determine your credit worthiness, we may use some of your Confidential Personal Information to request a credit report from a credit-reporting agency.

TDS uses the information collected on its Web sites to provide you with the information you requested. When you use our Web sites to order products or services, or to request information about them, we may use the information we have about you as we would use the same information obtained offline - for example, to evaluate your service needs and contact you regarding additional services you may find useful. You may also submit applications for employment online, and we will use the information you provide to consider you for employment. 

There may be instances when TDS may access or disclose Confidential Personal Information without notice or your consent in order to: (i) protect or defend the legal rights or property of TDS, our Affiliated Companies or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (ii) protect the safety and security of customers or members of the public including acting in urgent circumstances; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or (iv) comply with the law or legal process such as a subpoena. In addition, if TDS sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of all or a material part of its assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or transfer of all or a material part of its business, TDS may transfer your Confidential Personal Information to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction.

If we obtain Confidential Personal Information from a Third Party, our use of that information is also governed by this Privacy Statement.

### Collection and Use of Children's Confidential Personal Information

TDS's Web sites and services are intended for general audiences. In order to respect the privacy of children online, TDS does not knowingly collect, maintain or process Confidential Personal Information submitted by children under the age of 13. When one of our Web sites does collect age information, and users identify themselves as under 13, the site will block such users from providing Confidential Personal Information.

### Sharing of your Confidential Personal Information

We will not disclose your Confidential Personal Information without your express or implied consent outside of TDS, its Affiliates, or its authorized agents other than as described in this Privacy Statement. 

TDS may share Confidential Personal Information for purposes permitted by law without your consent such as to help initiate, render, bill, and collect for its products and services.

Your Confidential Personal Information may be shared with Affiliates and Third Parties with your consent for the purposes of marketing our products and services. Depending on the circumstance, notice and opt-out may be a permissible means of obtaining your consent.

Affiliates and Third Parties are permitted to obtain only the Confidential Personal Information they need and are prohibited from using it for any purpose other than those permitted by law or with your consent. When we use service providers to assist us in processing your Confidential Personal Information, we require that they comply with this Privacy Statement and maintain appropriate privacy and security measures. 

TDS does not sell your Confidential Personal Information to Third Parties for any purpose other than to enforce our rights under the Terms of Service or as expressly stated in this Privacy Statement. For example, we may sell past-due accounts receivable in an effort to collect for unpaid services. In addition, if TDS sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of all or a material part of its assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or transfer of all or a material part of its business, TDS may transfer your Confidential Personal Information to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction. 

**California Privacy Rights**

A business subject to California Civil Code section 1798.83 is required to disclose to its customers, upon request, the identity of any Third Parties to whom the business has disclosed "personal information" regarding that customer within the immediately preceding calendar year. 

If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to: 

TDS Telecom  
525 Junction Road  
Madison, WI 53717

Please note that California businesses are only required to respond to a customer request once during the course of any calendar year. 

### Customer Proprietary Network Information ("CPNI")

CPNI refers to and includes information that we have about you by virtue of our relationship with you as your service provider. This includes information about your account usage – such as the type and quantity of the services you subscribe to and other details about your calling including the date, time, call-to location, number called or number the call was received from, and minutes and charges of the call. Use of CPNI is subject to federal laws and regulations with which TDS is required to comply. 

We use CPNI to help us service your account when you call us with questions, to guard against fraudulent use of our network, to provision our services, or to generate and collect your bill. The CPNI rules recognize the value of our use of this information to serve you and permit our use of your information provided we safeguard it from unauthorized disclosure. We want to assure all of our customers that we have practices and procedures in place to help ensure your Confidential Personal Information is safe.

TDS is prohibited from allowing our Affiliates or agents from using this information without your permission for marketing TDS's or its Affiliates products and services to you. Your permission allows them to use this information to assist you with your needs.

When you become a customer of TDS and no later than every two years thereafter, we will send you a notice in the mail explaining your rights concerning Customer Proprietary Network Information ("CPNI Notice"). You can expect to receive the CPNI Notice in your bill (or by a separate mailing if you are enrolled in TDS ePay). It is important that you contact us as described in this notice if you do not wish to grant permission to use your CPNI to market new products and services to you. The law permits us to infer your permission if you do not tell us otherwise. 

**Access or Disclosure of CPNI**

There may be instances when TDS may access or disclose CPNI without notice or your consent in order to: (i) protect or defend the legal rights or property of TDS, our Affiliated Companies or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (ii) protect the safety and security of customers or members of the public including acting in urgent circumstances; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or (iv) comply with the law or legal process such as a subpoena. In addition, if TDS sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of all or a material part of its assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or transfer of all or a material part of its business, TDS may transfer your CPNI to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction.

For additional information about the FCC's rules pertaining to CPNI follow this link <http://www.fcc.gov/cgb/consumerfacts/phoneaboutyou.html>.

### Accessing your Confidential Personal Information

TDS takes reasonable measures to assure that the Confidential Personal Information we use about you is accurate, complete, and up-to-date. We make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your Confidential Personal Information either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes.

Customers who wish to review and/or edit their Confidential Personal Information may do so by contacting us at the number provided on their billing statement.

We may decline to process requests for information that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort.

TDS provides customers with the ability to authorize individuals ("Authorized User") to make inquiries, limited changes, or both, in order to maintain their account. Customers may specify the type of information and changes that the Authorized User is approved to request. This includes access to call detail. An Authorized User cannot change the customer's Confidential Personal Information. Customers may add or remove an Authorized User from their account at any time.

We ask customers and their Authorized Users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests. If you or your Authorized User contacts us via phone, you will be asked to provide your name, the account Personal Identification Number ("PIN") (if the account is PIN protected), and the billing address zip code before we are able to assist you. You or your Authorized user will be asked to present a valid photo ID when requesting account information while at a business office.

### Communication Preferences

If you do not want TDS to use your Confidential Personal Information to contact you for marketing or solicitation purposes (excluding notices about your existing account), you may make this request to [webcontact@tdstelecom.com](mailto:webcontact@tdstelecom.com) or to TDS Telecom, 525 Junction Road, Madison, Wisconsin 53717.

When writing to us, please specify which contact methods (phone calls, mail, bill inserts, or email messages) you would prefer that we do not use to communicate to you for the purposes outlined above. Keep in mind that restricting contact methods may make it more difficult for us to keep you informed about new products and services that can be of benefit to you. You can revoke these options at any time by contacting us using one of the methods provided.

These choices do not apply to the display of online advertising or the receipt of mandatory service communications that are considered part of certain TDS services, which you may receive periodically unless you cancel the service.

If you request to not be contacted by phone for marketing or sales purposes, please note that the TDS Do Not Call List restricts these types of phone contacts from TDS only, so you may continue to receive calls from other companies. If you would like to add your number to the National Do Not Call List, you may do so by calling 1-888-382-1222 or going online at [www.donotcall.gov](http://www.donotcall.gov/).

### Controlling Unsolicited Email ("Spam")

TDS is concerned about controlling unsolicited email or "spam." While TDS and its vendors continue to actively review and implement new technology to help prevent this activity, there is no currently available technology that will totally prevent the sending and receiving of unsolicited email. Using junk email tools and being cautious about the sharing of your email address while online will help reduce the amount of unsolicited email you receive. For more information about this and other related topics go to the Federal Trade Commission's website at [http://www.onguardonline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/).

### Security of your Confidential Personal Information

TDS takes reasonable security safeguards to protect against such risks as loss or unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure of Confidential Personal Information.

We restrict access to Confidential Personal Information to TDS employees, employees of our Affiliates, and authorized Third Parties who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

We protect the security of your Confidential Personal Information transmitted through our Web sites by using software which encrypts the Confidential Personal Information you input or view. 

Customers should not provide their account information or pin to anyone other than Authorized Users on their account. Customers are encouraged to protect their computer and passwords against unauthorized access. When accessing information online, customers should sign off when finished using a shared computer and always log out of any Web site after viewing Confidential Personal Information.

We will not store Confidential Personal Information beyond what is necessary for business purposes, including for internal service evaluation and quality assurance purposes, except as otherwise required by law.

### Enforcement of this Privacy Statement

Our employees, agents, and Affiliates are trained regarding their responsibilities to safeguard your privacy. They are required to adhere to a Code of Business Conduct, this Privacy Statement, and TDS's policies which support our commitment to protecting customer privacy. Failure to comply with the Code, this Privacy Statement, or TDS's policies may result in disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment.

If employees or Third Parties become aware of practices that raise privacy concerns, they are required to report them to their supervisors or to contact TDS's Incident Response Team.

### Changes to this Privacy Statement

We will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this Privacy Statement, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this Privacy Statement. If there are material changes to this Privacy Statement or in how TDS will use your Confidential Personal Information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes 30 days prior to implementing the change or we may make reasonable attempts to notify you directly. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be kept informed about TDS's privacy practices.

’ 

### Contacting Us

TDS welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you have questions about this Privacy Statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us by writing to us at the following address:

TDS Telecom  
525 Junction Road  
Madison, WI 53717
